<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>The Emerald Coast Real Estate Podcast with Scott Gregory</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Scott Gregory Team - your professional The Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Scott Gregory</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-03-11 13:07:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Scott Gregory</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>scottgregoryteam@gmail.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Scott Gregory</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the The Emerald Coast Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Scott Gregory Team - your professional The Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>We’re Excited to Help You Save With Our New VIP Club</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/were-excited-to-help-you-save-with-our-new-vip-club.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-04 12:37:24 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’re so thankful for all of you who have supported our business by trusting us with your real estate needs, and, because of this, we wanted to develop a way to show you our appreciation. 

Allow us to introduce our new VIP Club. We’ve partnered with Corporate Plus Club to bring you all sorts of discounts for businesses nationwide, including AMC movie theaters, professional sporting events, Six Flags, Choice and Wyndham Hotels, and Budget, Hertz, and Enterprise rental cars. We’re so excited to help you save. 

Plus, as a VIP, you’ll also receive exclusive invites to events we’ll host throughout the year. Those who do business with us, or refer business to us, are automatically granted a one-year “Inner Circle” membership that includes even more special benefits. Even if you’ve moved away from the Emerald Coast, we would be happy to refer you to an agent within our network wherever you are in America. 

“We’re so excited to help you save.”

Keep your eye out for a blue envelope, which will contain more membership information, coming from us soon. If you’ve done business with us and haven’t received your card soon, click this link to update your mailing address. Once you receive the VIP Club invite, use the code on the back of the card to download our free app on your smartphone to activate your membership and start saving right away. We encourage you to share your login with your entire family so that they can all save too.

Once again, thank you for your support. Welcome to the club!

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As our way of thanking you for your continued support, we’d like to invite you into our new VIP Club.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As our way of thanking you for your continued support, we’d like to invite you into our new VIP Club.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Make These 6 Mistakes When Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-make-these-6-mistakes-when-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-07 11:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Every seller wants their home to stand out from the crowd, and that often means beefing it up with shiny, new improvements before putting it on the market. Sometimes, however, owners go overboard and the repairs become more costly and time-consuming than they’re worth.

To help you learn from others’ mistakes, we gathered real-life stories of home sellers who woefully regret the pre-sale home renovations they took on:

1. Going too trendy. Beware of falling for decor fads when it comes time to spruce up your home. It’s best to stay with tried-and-true choices.

2. Smart house, dumb decision. Living in a house surrounded by technology is really not everyone’s cup of tea. You want to be modern, but don’t go overboard—it’ll turn off some buyers.

“Let’s face it—some home improvements are better left to the pros.”

3. Adding a guest house. Not every home shopper dreams of bringing in extra income by renting out a guest house. For some families, a rented guest house might be a little too close for comfort.

4. Rehabbing the roof. Replacing a major system like the roof may seem like a no-brainer to those seeking to attract buyers, but it’s not always worth it. Only do this if it’s a necessary fix.

5. DIYing to cut corners. Let’s face it—some home improvements are better left to the pros. Can you make your repair look as though a pro did it?

6. Opening Pandora’s box. It’s common to want to complete some home improvements before putting your home on the market, but doing so might plunge you headfirst into a mess that you weren’t prepared for.

As your real estate professional, don’t make any pre-sale changes to your home without consulting me first. You can reach out to me anytime—I’m here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Not all home improvement projects are necessarily value-boosters. Here’s a list of six home selling mistakes that have brought headaches to owners in the past.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Not all home improvement projects are necessarily value-boosters. Here’s a list of six home selling mistakes that have brought headaches to owners in the past.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Opportunities eXp Realty Can Bring You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-opportunities-exp-realty-can-bring-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-14 11:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re considering a career change and looking to get into real estate, or you’re already in the real estate business and looking to join another company, today’s message is for you. 

I’m more excited about what the Scott Gregory Team is doing right now than I’ve been at any point in my two decades in real estate. The reason why is the opportunities we have working with the agent-owned, cloud-based brokerage, eXp Realty—not to mention the fantastic people we’ve gone in business with through our contractor agreement with the company. 

Previously in my career, I spent 12 years at KW Realty, and I loved it. They have a great model for a traditional brokerage, and I thought I’d never leave. I’m also a real estate coach, though, and when one of my coaching clients moved over to eXp, she was thrilled about the move and asked me if I knew anything about the company. I told her I knew everything about it…or so I thought. 

The truth is, I hadn’t actually seen eXp’s presentation, so out of respect to my coaching client, I decided to take a look at it. Once I saw it, I couldn’t unsee it. Several minutes in, I was at the edge of my seat. They turned the traditional brokerage model on its head—some would call them the Amazon of real estate. They got rid of brick-and-mortar offices, which means lower fees. Also, some of the money that traditionally goes back to the franchise owner or ownership group is given back to the agents in the form of revenue sharing. 

“There are more than 300 eXp employees staffing their cloud, and they provide all the training and support you could ever need.”

Can you imagine what would be possible if you received a percentage of hundreds or even thousands of deals without any expense? Additionally, the company gives stock back to agents once they reach different milestones. There’s even a milestone where, if you reach it, you get back everything you pay into the company in a given year in the form of stock. 

What I saw in that presentation was an opportunity to get paid three ways. I also saw an opportunity for my team members to build additional streams of revenue outside of real estate sales. There are more than 300 eXp employees staffing their cloud, and they provide all the training and support you could ever need—there are five to seven daily classes you can take from your computer. More importantly, they offer the systems and technology I need to run my business to its full potential and support my buyers and sellers. 

You absolutely owe it to yourself to check this model out. What you’ll find is that agents will come to you to find out why you’re so excited about what you’re doing. 

If you’re thinking about joining a team, we’d love to talk to you about the systems we offer that give you the leads to do more business and make a better life for yourself outside of real estate.Also, if you’d like to watch some free webinars about how to improve your real estate business, visit our website www.grittyagents.com 

If you have any other questions or concerns, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m more excited about what our team is doing right now than I’ve ever been. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m more excited about what our team is doing right now than I’ve ever been. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Make Any of These Home Selling Mistakes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-make-any-of-these-home-selling-mistakes.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-18 16:34:15 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Selling a home is an emotional process and one that can make sellers susceptible to all sorts of pitfalls along the way, such as:

1. Forgetting about curb appeal. If you can’t get a buyer through the front door, the interior improvements you make don’t really matter. Now is the time to lay new sod, plant new hedges and colorful flowers, and create an inviting environment to set the stage for your buyers to fall in love.

2. Pricing the home too high. One of the biggest mistakes a seller can make is pricing their home above market value. Many sellers think they can just reduce the price later if need be, but by pricing correctly from the beginning, it will sell faster and for the most money possible.

3. Not preparing the home for sale. Many sellers will disregard easy steps such as staging and decluttering before putting their home on the market. A real estate sale is like selling any other product. Delivery is paramount to its success. Neglecting to make needed repairs is another big mistake because the repairs will likely end up being more expensive later and result in a lower sales price for your home.

“Neglecting to make needed repairs is another big mistake.”

4. Investing in unnecessary upgrades. Remodeling a kitchen or bathroom is a large undertaking and involves a lot of preference. Doing this right before selling rarely improves the return on investment, especially when the carrying costs to the renovations are considered.

5. Taking low offers personally. I know it’s easy to do so, but if a low offer comes in, just think of it as a starting point for negotiation. It’s important to keep a level head during this process.

If you have any questions for me about this topic or about anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Selling a home in this market can be tough, but it’s easier if you know which mistakes to avoid. Here is some great advice for selling a home in this market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Selling a home in this market can be tough, but it’s easier if you know which mistakes to avoid. Here is some great advice for selling a home in this market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Scott Gregory</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Scott Gregory</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Scott Gregory Team - your professional The Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
