<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>The Emerald Coast Real Estate Podcast with Scott Gregory</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Scott Gregory Team - your professional The Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Scott Gregory</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2022-04-14 07:53:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Scott Gregory</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>scottgregoryteam@gmail.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Scott Gregory</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the The Emerald Coast Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Scott Gregory Team - your professional The Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Much Will You Really Net After Selling Your Home?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-much-will-you-really-net-after-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-30 13:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Many people wonder what kind of profit they’ll walk away with when they sell their home. After all, it’s what you net at the end of the sale, not the sales price, that matters most. 

Our team’s top priority is helping sellers get the most money in the least amount of time, and one of the tools we use to help us achieve this is our net sheet. 

At the very beginning of your deal, we’ll meet to discuss what the right price for your home is based on its condition, location, and features, but also on your goals and personal moving time frame. It’s after this conversation that we develop our net sheet, which covers the expected closing costs based upon the sales price we determined earlier. We also encourage buyers to talk to their lender about what their loan pay-off amount is. 

“We will need to speak one-on-one about your specific home before we can explain what your net profit will be.”

And remember, any outstanding debt (like your mortgage, taxes, and any liens that may be on the property) will be taken out of the net proceeds. 

Once you’ve figured out how much of a reduction this will constitute, we can then determine what your net proceeds will be.

After that, we will market your home aggressively in order to ensure optimal results for your sale. 

The bottom line is that we will need to speak one-on-one about your specific home before we can explain what your net profit will be. 

So, if you have any other questions, would like more information, or are curious about what we can do for your real estate goals, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon. 

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What will you earn at the end of your home sale? Let’s discuss.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What will you earn at the end of your home sale? Let’s discuss.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Some Lenders Can Derail Your Home Purchase</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-some-lenders-can-derail-your-home-purchase.html</link>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-20 13:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/Why+It's+Important+to+Work+With+a+Good+Lender.mp4</guid>
        <description>

My team has worked with hundreds of buyers over the years, and it still shocks me how little discussion some buyers have with their lenders about the finances involved in the home purchase.

This is something that should not and cannot be allowed to happen. Far too many times, we’ve had a buyer reach out to us with a pre-qualification or pre-approval letter hoping it will help the purchase go smoother. 

However, people who’ve decided to get their loan from “call-center lenders,” as opposed to a quality, local lender or broker, have walked away with pre-qualification letters in which the lender didn’t even pull their credit. When they get under contract, they realize they won’t qualify for the loan because of credit issues, and now they’ve wasted both time and money.

“Some lenders just assume that buyers know all about the process.”

Some lenders don’t take the time to talk about how much money a buyer will need at closing. They assume that buyers know all about the process and what their bottom line is, but that’s not always the case. Remember, you’ll need money for your down payment and for your share of the closing costs. Buyers assume they can roll all of the costs into a loan, but it isn’t as easy to do as it used to be with more lending regulations.

If you and your lender are on the same page with how much your out-of-pocket expenses will be, we can help you structure an offer that reflects your budget. The time to find out you don’t have the funds to close isn’t after you’ve already gone under contract.

If you need a list of great, local lenders who take time to work with you to ensure a smooth transaction, reach out to us today. We’d also be happy to answer any questions you have in the meantime. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/Why+It's+Important+to+Work+With+a+Good+Lender.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/Why+It's+Important+to+Work+With+a+Good+Lender.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I believe that lenders need to be more transparent with their home-buying clients, because bad things happen when they aren’t. Here’s what I mean.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I believe that lenders need to be more transparent with their home-buying clients, because bad things happen when they aren’t. Here’s what I mean.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What a Pre-Listing Inspection Can Do for Your Home Sale</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-a-pre-listing-inspection-can-do-for-your-home-sale.html</link>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-26 09:57:57 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/What+a+Pre-Listing+Inspection+Can+Do+for+Your+Home+Sale.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Given how stressful the real estate experience can be for both buyers and sellers, the last thing you want is to encounter an unwelcome surprise just weeks before you’re supposed to be closing. 

As the seller, you can eliminate the possibility of future surprises by having a pre-listing inspection done before your home hits the market. A pre-sale inspection works like any other home inspection. A professional inspector will come out to your property to examine its roof, structure, and mechanical systems, all the while recording any issues they uncover. Once their report is complete, you can seek the help of a handyman to make all the necessary repairs, resulting in a clean report. 

Having a pre-listing inspection done on your home offers peace of mind. For one thing, you won’t lie awake at night wondering if an inspection surprise will foil your home sale as you’re moving through the selling process. 

It’s also important to think about it from the buyer’s perspective: The morning after they enter into a contract to purchase your home, your buyer will wake up wondering if they made the right move. All buyers experience some degree of buyer’s remorse—most of which stems from fear of the unknown. If we can present them with an upfront, clean inspection report authored by a professional, you’ll have a decisive advantage over your competition, which all but guarantees a quicker, more profitable sale. 

“We’re currently in the middle of a market shift, which makes it all the more important to be strategic and competitive with our listings.”

Plus, when your buyer brings in their own inspector (and they most likely will), the chances that any issues come up will be much lower. Not to mention that some buyers will decide against having their own inspection done if you’ve already completed one.

We’re currently in the middle of a market shift, which makes it all the more important to be strategic and competitive with our listings. A pre-listing inspection is one of the best ways to do so. 

As a bonus, if you list your home with me, I’ll even reimburse you for the cost of the pre-listing inspection at closing. Just let me know that you’d like to take advantage of my Certified Pre-Owned Program. 

If you have any further questions or would like more details, please don’t hesitate to let me know. I look forward to hearing from you!  
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/What+a+Pre-Listing+Inspection+Can+Do+for+Your+Home+Sale.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/What+a+Pre-Listing+Inspection+Can+Do+for+Your+Home+Sale.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How can you keep your sale intact and on its way to close? A pre-listing inspection is how.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How can you keep your sale intact and on its way to close? A pre-listing inspection is how.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Have You Activated Your VIP Card Yet?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/have-you-activated-your-vip-card-yet.html</link>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-06 15:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+Some+Information+About+Our+VIP+Card.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’ve done business with my team or referred us, you’ve received our new Scott Gregory Team VIP Card via snail mail recently. We wanted a way to say thank you to all who have done business with us and referred business to us over the years.

Make sure you activate your card and then put it in your wallet or purse. Then, download the “Corporate Club” app on your iPhone or Android phone to start taking advantage of the savings and promotions it offers. All you have to do is enter the number on your card and you and your family can start saving.

“Save on hotels, rental cars, movie tickets, and more.”

You’ll get all sorts of discounts at businesses nationwide, including discounts at:


  AMC movie theatres
  Professionals sporting events
  Six Flags
  Choice and Wyndham Hotels
  Budget, Hertz, and Enterprise car rentals


For our VIPs along the Emerald Coast, we’ll continue working to get you great deals from your favorite local businesses as well. As a VIP, you’ll also get invited to special parties and events that we hold throughout the year. Those that do business with us and refer business to us each year will also earn an additional year of inner circle membership, which earns even more benefits.

For those who have moved away from the Emerald Coast, we can connect you with our network of outstanding agents anywhere in America.

To join our VIP Program, click here. 

If you haven’t received your card yet or you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+Some+Information+About+Our+VIP+Card.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+Some+Information+About+Our+VIP+Card.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>We wanted a way to say thank you to everyone who has done business with us. Introducing the Scott Gregory Team VIP Card.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>We wanted a way to say thank you to everyone who has done business with us. Introducing the Scott Gregory Team VIP Card.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Can You Do If You’re Behind on Your Mortgage Payments?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-can-you-do-if-youre-behind-on-your-mortgage-payments.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-06 23:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+What+Can+You+Do+if+Youre+Behind+on+Your+Mortgage+Payments_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re behind on your mortgage payments and don’t see your situation improving, you might be thinking that the only way out of this mess is to sell your home, but can you?

Absolutely. If you’re suffering some sort of hardship, you should be able to sell your home whether you have equity or not, and you can do so up until the mortgage company takes the property back by foreclosure. You can be behind on your payments and still make money from the sale if you have equity, which means the house is worth more than what’s owed on the mortgage plus what you’ll pay in closing costs. 

This is no different than a regular sale. All you have to do is get a full payoff letter from the lender or their attorney and bring it with you when you meet your agent. Don’t just go off of what your statement says, because there may be other fees that need to be settled. 

If your home isn’t worth what you owe, the bank may allow you to do a short sale to avoid a foreclosure or bankruptcy. This gets you out of your hardship faster with less of a credit hit and puts you on the path to homeownership and better credit. We’ve helped more than 200 families this way. The bank will even cover your closing costs if they approve your short sale. 

“If your home isn’t worth what you owe, the bank may allow you to do a short sale to avoid a foreclosure or bankruptcy.”

If you’ve fallen behind on your mortgage payments but you’d like to stay in the home, there are a couple of ways you can get back on track. 

First, you might be able to qualify for a mortgage forbearance, which is where your servicer gives you a temporary break from your payments and lets you get caught up. 

You can also get a loan modification, in which case your mortgage lender agrees to change the terms of your loans. Banks tend to shy away from loan modifications, though, because of complications with investors and the fact that most homeowners who receive modifications go back into default quickly because the underlying problems remain. 

If you need legal advice for financial problems, by all means, seek it. If you need to sell your home as a regular sale or a short sale, call me and we’ll get the job done for you. 

If you have any other questions, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d be happy to speak with you.  
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+What+Can+You+Do+if+Youre+Behind+on+Your+Mortgage+Payments_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+What+Can+You+Do+if+Youre+Behind+on+Your+Mortgage+Payments_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’ve fallen behind on your mortgage payments, you have options that allow you to either sell the home or stay in it and get back on track.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’ve fallen behind on your mortgage payments, you have options that allow you to either sell the home or stay in it and get back on track.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Real Value of Homeownership</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-real-value-of-homeownership.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-23 04:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+The+Real+Value+of+Homeownership.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Recently, social media business celebrities Gary Vaynerchuk and Grant Cardone have started taking shots at homeownership, calling it a bad idea.

Their position is that if you took that money you spent on your mortgage payment, and instead invested in rental properties that bring positive cash flow, it would be a smarter financial move. It doesn’t throw off positive cash each month, so it’s not a good investment, they say.

While I agree with them in theory, this is ridiculous in practice. 

First, you have to live somewhere. If you’re an adult and your parents will let you live with them rent-free for the next 40 or 50 years, maybe you should go for it!

But if you’ve instead made the decision to live life on your own, or your parents aren’t down with that long-term plan, then this is a problem.

You have to pay rent. And rent can cost more than your mortgage would in many markets. Even if it’s a little less, you are building zero equity, and you don’t get the tax savings that home ownership brings.

If you pay $1,000 a month rent for five years, that’s $60,000 in rent payments with nothing to show for it.

And let’s put money aside for a second and instead think about how great it would be to have a house to call your home. When you own a property, you can work to make it exactly as you and your family want it. You can’t do this in a rental.

With all of that said, let’s get back to the numbers. 

First-time homebuyers tend to focus on two things: the price of the home they’re buying, and the monthly payment. That’s entirely understandable.

There’s something else to consider: the future value of the home.

Appreciation, or the rising of home prices over time, is how the majority of wealth is built in real estate. That makes real estate one of the more stable long-term investments.

Prices don’t always go up, yet history has shown a solid appreciation over time. But what if the prices go down?

“The earlier you buy, the more wealth you have the opportunity to create.”

That’s never pleasant in the short term, but when it happens, you’re basically doing the same thing you’d be doing paying rent, aren’t you? On top of that, homeownership still gives you tax benefits that renting doesn’t.

Paying off a mortgage during your working years also allows you to remove a large expense from your plate during retirement.

My dad often said to me that paying off the house was the best thing he ever did financially. He and my mom were able to enjoy a nice retirement due mainly to the equity they had built in their home.

I’ll be blunt: Without their home equity, there would have been no retirement for them. You can shave almost eight years off a 30-year mortgage by just making one more mortgage payment applied to your principal balance per year. 

Let’s face it: Everything has gotten so much more expensive. For those struggling to put money away, paying a mortgage can create a savings cushion that renting cannot.

Owning a home does not guarantee a higher net worth, nor does it remove the need to be financially responsible. However, it does provide a structure within which one can build wealth. It also provides a setting for you to enjoy your life more freely with your family.

The earlier you buy, the more wealth you have the opportunity to create. What you do today can absolutely affect your future financial picture.

So enjoy the benefits of homeownership. And as your wealth grows, then you can start thinking about investing to bring some additional cash flow into your life. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+The+Real+Value+of+Homeownership.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+The+Real+Value+of+Homeownership.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Is homeownership worth it? Today I’d like to explain why I believe it absolutely is.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Is homeownership worth it? Today I’d like to explain why I believe it absolutely is.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 House-Hunting Tips for Buyers to Bear in Mind</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/5-house-hunting-tips-for-buyers-to-bear-in-mind.html</link>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-30 11:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+5+House-Hunting+Tips+for+Buyers+to+Bear+in+Mind.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Let’s face it: House-hunt burnout can be a reality for buyers, but there are ways you can keep your stress level down and sanity even-keeled. Here are five tips to do so: 

1. Get pre-approved first. Meet with a mortgage professional before you even think about diving into the MLS to figure out what you can afford. Knowing your affordability up front will help you develop an early idea of what you’re willing to spend and will allow you to act quickly when your dream home comes onto the market. 

2. Make a “must-have” list and stick to it. No house will have all the qualities that you’re looking for, so decide what you can’t live without. This will allow you to narrow your focus without placing too much emphasis on what’s less important. In that same way, consider zeroing in on a particular neighborhood—your criteria could include amenities, the school district, or whatever else is important to you. Explore the area that lines up with your criteria before committing.  

3. Pick just one house style. Once you’ve made up your mind, resist the urge to explore outside the bounds of that particular style. If you want a single-story house, for example, don’t bother with townhomes, multi-level homes, etc.

“Explore the area that lines up with your criteria before committing.”

4. Document your home visits. As you walk through the home, capture pictures of every facet you like about it—a few examples might be the killer view or a to-die-for kitchen. By the same token, taking pictures will allow you to capture things that seem out of place, like a scary shag carpet or a funky layout. Be sure to take notes on the listing sheet, so that what you were trying to capture can quickly come to mind.   

5. Limit your decision to three contenders. If a certain home doesn’t make the cut, then forget about it. At some point, it’s time to decide and you’ll need to have a short list ready to go. There’s no need to see dozens of properties; that’ll just ultimately create more stress and confusion. Base your decisions on what’s most important and look at the best choices. 

I hope you found value in today’s five house-hunting tips. When it’s time for you to buy your next home, reach out to my team and me and ask us about our VIP Buyer Program that will save you both time and money. We look forward to hearing from you!    
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+5+House-Hunting+Tips+for+Buyers+to+Bear+in+Mind.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Scott+Gregory+/Scott+Gregory+Real+Estate+_+5+House-Hunting+Tips+for+Buyers+to+Bear+in+Mind.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You don't want to get burnt out while looking for a new home. Here are a few tips to help you avoid it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You don't want to get burnt out while looking for a new home. Here are a few tips to help you avoid it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Forget These Important Steps During Your Move</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-forget-these-important-steps-during-your-move.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-11 14:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

The process of finding and buying a new home is a whirlwind in and of itself, but don’t let the hustle and bustle keep you from sorting out some important details during your move. Along with adjusting to your new mortgage payments, there are several other factors you’ll need to keep in mind as you get settled into your new home. 

Here are just a few steps to stay on top of during this transition:


  Switch your bank.
  Empty your safety deposit box. 
  Transfer prescriptions to your new pharmacy. 
  Find a new healthcare provider. 
  Transfer local memberships (like gym memberships). 
  Ask your children’s school administrators for copies of their records.
  Raid your kitchen. About a month before you move, start thawing out the items you’ve had sitting in your refrigerator so that the unit is clean and empty before moving day. 
  Get your car checked up. 


If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re about to move, follow this checklist to ensure a smooth transition.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re about to move, follow this checklist to ensure a smooth transition.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7 Tips for Staying Safe in Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/7-tips-for-staying-safe-in-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-22 15:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

It’s safe to say that no one creates hazards in a home on purpose. However, no matter how hard we try, accidents still happen. There’s nothing more important than protecting our families, ourselves, and our investment in our homes.

According to StaySafe, accidents in the home claim 18,000 lives each year and account for 21 million medical visits. Many of these deaths and visits are preventable. Here are some tips to keep you and your family safe:

1. Check your dryer vents frequently. Thousands of fires start each year due to a dirty vent. Most of us clean the lint screen, but, over time, lint sneaks into the vent and could clog it. Consider having a professional come out to clean the vent at least once every two years. I’ve pulled a six-foot lint snake out of my dryer vent before.

2. Keep a fire extinguisher nearby. Having one in the laundry room isn’t a bad idea, because fires tend to happen there.

3. Watch for potential fall hazards. People of all ages are susceptible to fall injuries, which are responsible for a third of all fatalities in America. Install safety gates at the top and bottom of your stairs if you have kids, and put non-slip pads underneath bath mats and rugs.


  “People of all ages are susceptible to fall injuries.”


4. Consider cordless blinds.

5. Keep your fire alarm batteries current. Check and change them at least once a year. There are smart smoke detectors that you can buy to remotely monitor things.

6. Add carbon monoxide detectors to your home.

7. Clear out ash from your fireplace or fire pit. I once watered down ash from our fire pit a week after the fire and it relit in the garbage can. Be safe out there everyone.

If you have any questions for me in the meantime or any real estate needs that I can assist with, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Your home is full of hazards. Here’s how to avoid them.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Your home is full of hazards. Here’s how to avoid them.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>We’re Excited to Help You Save With Our New VIP Club</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/were-excited-to-help-you-save-with-our-new-vip-club.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-04 12:37:24 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’re so thankful for all of you who have supported our business by trusting us with your real estate needs, and, because of this, we wanted to develop a way to show you our appreciation. 

Allow us to introduce our new VIP Club. We’ve partnered with Corporate Plus Club to bring you all sorts of discounts for businesses nationwide, including AMC movie theaters, professional sporting events, Six Flags, Choice and Wyndham Hotels, and Budget, Hertz, and Enterprise rental cars. We’re so excited to help you save. 

Plus, as a VIP, you’ll also receive exclusive invites to events we’ll host throughout the year. Those who do business with us, or refer business to us, are automatically granted a one-year “Inner Circle” membership that includes even more special benefits. Even if you’ve moved away from the Emerald Coast, we would be happy to refer you to an agent within our network wherever you are in America. 

“We’re so excited to help you save.”

Keep your eye out for a blue envelope, which will contain more membership information, coming from us soon. If you’ve done business with us and haven’t received your card soon, click this link to update your mailing address. Once you receive the VIP Club invite, use the code on the back of the card to download our free app on your smartphone to activate your membership and start saving right away. We encourage you to share your login with your entire family so that they can all save too.

Once again, thank you for your support. Welcome to the club!

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>As our way of thanking you for your continued support, we’d like to invite you into our new VIP Club.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>As our way of thanking you for your continued support, we’d like to invite you into our new VIP Club.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Make These 6 Mistakes When Selling Your Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-make-these-6-mistakes-when-selling-your-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-07 11:17:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Every seller wants their home to stand out from the crowd, and that often means beefing it up with shiny, new improvements before putting it on the market. Sometimes, however, owners go overboard and the repairs become more costly and time-consuming than they’re worth.

To help you learn from others’ mistakes, we gathered real-life stories of home sellers who woefully regret the pre-sale home renovations they took on:

1. Going too trendy. Beware of falling for decor fads when it comes time to spruce up your home. It’s best to stay with tried-and-true choices.

2. Smart house, dumb decision. Living in a house surrounded by technology is really not everyone’s cup of tea. You want to be modern, but don’t go overboard—it’ll turn off some buyers.

“Let’s face it—some home improvements are better left to the pros.”

3. Adding a guest house. Not every home shopper dreams of bringing in extra income by renting out a guest house. For some families, a rented guest house might be a little too close for comfort.

4. Rehabbing the roof. Replacing a major system like the roof may seem like a no-brainer to those seeking to attract buyers, but it’s not always worth it. Only do this if it’s a necessary fix.

5. DIYing to cut corners. Let’s face it—some home improvements are better left to the pros. Can you make your repair look as though a pro did it?

6. Opening Pandora’s box. It’s common to want to complete some home improvements before putting your home on the market, but doing so might plunge you headfirst into a mess that you weren’t prepared for.

As your real estate professional, don’t make any pre-sale changes to your home without consulting me first. You can reach out to me anytime—I’m here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Not all home improvement projects are necessarily value-boosters. Here’s a list of six home selling mistakes that have brought headaches to owners in the past.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Not all home improvement projects are necessarily value-boosters. Here’s a list of six home selling mistakes that have brought headaches to owners in the past.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Opportunities eXp Realty Can Bring You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-opportunities-exp-realty-can-bring-you.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-14 11:02:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re considering a career change and looking to get into real estate, or you’re already in the real estate business and looking to join another company, today’s message is for you. 

I’m more excited about what the Scott Gregory Team is doing right now than I’ve been at any point in my two decades in real estate. The reason why is the opportunities we have working with the agent-owned, cloud-based brokerage, eXp Realty—not to mention the fantastic people we’ve gone in business with through our contractor agreement with the company. 

Previously in my career, I spent 12 years at KW Realty, and I loved it. They have a great model for a traditional brokerage, and I thought I’d never leave. I’m also a real estate coach, though, and when one of my coaching clients moved over to eXp, she was thrilled about the move and asked me if I knew anything about the company. I told her I knew everything about it…or so I thought. 

The truth is, I hadn’t actually seen eXp’s presentation, so out of respect to my coaching client, I decided to take a look at it. Once I saw it, I couldn’t unsee it. Several minutes in, I was at the edge of my seat. They turned the traditional brokerage model on its head—some would call them the Amazon of real estate. They got rid of brick-and-mortar offices, which means lower fees. Also, some of the money that traditionally goes back to the franchise owner or ownership group is given back to the agents in the form of revenue sharing. 

“There are more than 300 eXp employees staffing their cloud, and they provide all the training and support you could ever need.”

Can you imagine what would be possible if you received a percentage of hundreds or even thousands of deals without any expense? Additionally, the company gives stock back to agents once they reach different milestones. There’s even a milestone where, if you reach it, you get back everything you pay into the company in a given year in the form of stock. 

What I saw in that presentation was an opportunity to get paid three ways. I also saw an opportunity for my team members to build additional streams of revenue outside of real estate sales. There are more than 300 eXp employees staffing their cloud, and they provide all the training and support you could ever need—there are five to seven daily classes you can take from your computer. More importantly, they offer the systems and technology I need to run my business to its full potential and support my buyers and sellers. 

You absolutely owe it to yourself to check this model out. What you’ll find is that agents will come to you to find out why you’re so excited about what you’re doing. 

If you’re thinking about joining a team, we’d love to talk to you about the systems we offer that give you the leads to do more business and make a better life for yourself outside of real estate.Also, if you’d like to watch some free webinars about how to improve your real estate business, visit our website www.grittyagents.com 

If you have any other questions or concerns, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I’m more excited about what our team is doing right now than I’ve ever been. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I’m more excited about what our team is doing right now than I’ve ever been. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Make Any of These Home Selling Mistakes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dont-make-any-of-these-home-selling-mistakes.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Scott Gregory</author>
        <pubDate>2018-12-18 16:34:15 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Selling a home is an emotional process and one that can make sellers susceptible to all sorts of pitfalls along the way, such as:

1. Forgetting about curb appeal. If you can’t get a buyer through the front door, the interior improvements you make don’t really matter. Now is the time to lay new sod, plant new hedges and colorful flowers, and create an inviting environment to set the stage for your buyers to fall in love.

2. Pricing the home too high. One of the biggest mistakes a seller can make is pricing their home above market value. Many sellers think they can just reduce the price later if need be, but by pricing correctly from the beginning, it will sell faster and for the most money possible.

3. Not preparing the home for sale. Many sellers will disregard easy steps such as staging and decluttering before putting their home on the market. A real estate sale is like selling any other product. Delivery is paramount to its success. Neglecting to make needed repairs is another big mistake because the repairs will likely end up being more expensive later and result in a lower sales price for your home.

“Neglecting to make needed repairs is another big mistake.”

4. Investing in unnecessary upgrades. Remodeling a kitchen or bathroom is a large undertaking and involves a lot of preference. Doing this right before selling rarely improves the return on investment, especially when the carrying costs to the renovations are considered.

5. Taking low offers personally. I know it’s easy to do so, but if a low offer comes in, just think of it as a starting point for negotiation. It’s important to keep a level head during this process.

If you have any questions for me about this topic or about anything else related to real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Selling a home in this market can be tough, but it’s easier if you know which mistakes to avoid. Here is some great advice for selling a home in this market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Scott Gregory</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Selling a home in this market can be tough, but it’s easier if you know which mistakes to avoid. Here is some great advice for selling a home in this market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in The Emerald Coast, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Scott Gregory</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Scott Gregory</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Scott Gregory Team - your professional The Emerald Coast Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
